NILKANTH S. DALVI

Environment, Health & Safety

Phone: 8097049633/9420525960

Email: nilkanthdalvi33@gmail.com

smartnil06@gmail.com

Address: Navratna CHS Ltd; A/9, 2nd Floor, Old Dombivli, Dombivli (W), Thane, Maharashtra – 421202,

Personal Details:

Date of Birth: 10th December 1987

Gender: Male

Nationality: Indian

Key skills

- Leadership
- Communication
- Time management
- Collaboration
- Presentation
- Technical knowledge

Software

- Amethyst Shadow
- AutoCAD
- AERMOD
- Ecotect
- MS Office

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Marathi

Areas of Expertise

- Environmental Audit
- Water Audit
- Water Treatment Plant
- Traffic Impact Assessment
- Shadow Analysis
- Air & Noise Pollution
- Report Making
- PCB Liasoning Work

Summary

Goal-oriented Environment & Safety Expert with 8+ years of experience. Working in Environmental Sector dealing with Project on Environmental Clearance, EIA, MPCB Liasoning, Waste Water Treatment, and Research Project in Environment, Government Liasoning, Environmental Audits and Water Audits etc.

Completed post graduate in Environmental Science with a Masters' Degree from Mumbai University and Advance Diploma in Industrial Safety from MSBTE.

Experience

01.11.2017 to Present **Assistant Manager** | Enviro Policy Research India Pvt. Ltd, Thane

- Environmental Audit
- Water Audit of Indian Railways
- Pollution Control Board Liasoning
- Environmental Clearance (EC)
- Environmental Impact Assessment (EIA)
- Traffic Impact Assessment
- Shadow Analysis
- Disaster Management Plan
- Day Light, UHI Assessment
- Emission Inventory of 10 Cities
- Noise Monitoring of 10 Cities
- Dust suppressant research work CPCB
- Air Filtration Unit
- Solid Waste Management

Key Achievement:

- Nominated as Project Manager for Emission Inventory & Noise Monitoring suggested by NEERI
- Nominated as Project Manager for Demonstration of Dust Suppressant in Delhi; funded by Central Pollution Control Board

15.06.2013–31.10.2017 *Environmental Engineer* | Eco Rise Youth Innovations, Panvel

- Design, Erection & commissioning of Water Treatment Plants
- MSME, CGWA Documentation
- Pollution Control Board Liasoning
- Environmental Monitoring
- Effluent Treatment Plant Supervision
- Laboratory Analysis

Key Achievement:

- Completion of Major Project within budget & time period (2016)
- Employee of the Year (2015)

Project Work

- Safety in Chemical Industry
- Disaster Management Plan (DMP) of Nuclear Power Plant
- Environment Impact
 Assessment (EIA) of Mining
 Industry
- Ecotourism of Dapoli (Dist. Ratnagiri, Maharashtra)
- Legal Case Study of Tiger Trade

Research Work

- Biofuel production from Cotton seed oil
- Management of Mango Crop in Ratnagiri

Training

- Industrial Safety DFPCL, Taloja
- Waste Water Treatment Gadre Marine, Ratnagiri

Publications

 Research paper on Dust Control Study

Participation

- Poster Competitions World Ozone Day organized by University of Mumbai
- National Conference on Industry Expectations from Safety Manager organized by VPM Polytechnic, Thane
- International Conference on Waste to Energy organized by WTERT, Hyderabad
- Conference on Statistical Approaches in Biological Sciences organized by Gogate College, Ratnagiri

20.07.2012–20.05.2013 *Environmental Engineer* | Green Scientific Development (I) Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai

- Pollution Control Board Liasoning
- Environmental Monitoring
- Environmental Audit
- Effluent Treatment Plant Supervision

06.06.2011–30.06.2012 *ETP Supervisor* | Fair Brothers Associates, Mumbai

- Effluent Treatment Plant Supervision
- Lab Reporting

Education

2015: Advance Diploma in Industrial Safety

Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education V.P.M, Polytechnic, Thane

Grade: First Class

Relevant coursework:

- Environment Management
- Chemical Safety
- Construction Safety
- Safety in Engineering

2011: Master of Science, Environmental Science

Mumbai University, Sub Centre Mumbai University, Ratnagiri Grade: First Class

Relevant coursework:

- Environment Management
- Biodiversity
- Waste Water

2008: Bachelor of Science, Botany

Mumbai University, Gogate- Jogalekar College, Ratnagiri Grade : First Class

2005: HSC (12th)

Pune Board , Gogate- Jogalekar College, Ratnagiri Grade : Second Class

2003: HSC (10th)

Kolhapur Board, S.M.M.V.K. High School, Ratnagiri

Grade: First Class

Certifications

- Diploma in Software Engineering
- Internal Quality Auditor (ISO 9001:2015, ISO 14001:2015 & BS 18001:2007)

Declaration

I attest that the above information relating to my Education & Experience is correct.

TSadvi

NILKANTH SATYAWAN DALVI

DATE: